《疯狂的麦克斯2》
我的生命在凋逝
My life fades...
视线渐渐模糊
...the vision dims.
剩下的只有回忆
All that remains are memories.
我记得 混乱的时光…
I remember a time of chaos...
毁去的梦想 这片被糟蹋的土地
...ruined dreams, this wasted land.
但一切之中 我记得的是公路战士
But most of all, I remember the Road Warrior...
我们叫他麦克斯
...the man we called Max.
要了解他是谁 必须回到另一个时代…
To understand who he was, you have to go back to another time...
当世界仍以黑色燃油作为能量来源…
...when the world was powered by the black fuel...
沙漠里出现了有着钢铁和管线的大城市
...and the deserts sprouted great cities of pipe and steel.
现在都没了 消失的一干二净
Gone now, swept away.
为了早被忘掉的原因 两个强大的战士部落发生战争…
For reasons long forgotten, two mighty warrior tribes went to war...
触发了一场大火 吞噬了一切
...and touched off a blaze which engulfed them all.
没有了燃料 他们什么都不是了 用稻草盖了房子
Without fuel they were nothing. They'd built a house of straw.
雷声隆隆的机器 发出劈拍声后停了下来
The thundering machines sputtered and stopped.
他们的领导人谈了又谈… 又再谈
Their leaders talked and talked and talked.
但没有什么能阻止崩溃
But nothing could stem the avalanche.
他们的世界瓦解了
Their world crumbled...
城市被炸毁了
...the cities exploded.
掠夺的旋风…
A whirlwind of looting...
恐惧的火灾
...a firestorm of fear.
人开始吃人
Men began to feed on men.
公路上到处是白色恐怖的梦魇
On the roads, it was a white-line nightmare.
只有行动力够到处觅食的…
Only those mobile enough to scavenge...
残忍得能掠夺的 才活得下来
...brutal enough to pillage, would survive.
帮派接管了高速公路…
The gangs took over the highways...
为了一箱橘子汁准备发动战争
...ready to wage war for a tank of juice.
在这样衰退的大混乱里…
And in this maelstrom of decay...
普通人会被撕成碎片
...ordinary men were battered and smashed.
像麦克斯这样的人
Men like Max.
战士麦克斯
The warrior Max.
在引擎的怒吼声里 他失去了一切…
In the roar of an engine, he lost everything...
成了只剩空壳的人
...and became a shell of a man.
一个累坏而寂寞的男人
A burnt-out, desolate man.
过去被恶魔追逐的男人
A man haunted by the demons of his past.
一位流荡到荒漠里的人
A man who wandered out into the wasteland.
就是这里…
And it was here...
在这个枯竭之地…
...in this blighted place...
他学着重生
...that he learned to live again.
(油量)
(小心)
(地球)
别伤了那蛇 放下它
Don't hurt the snake. Put it down.
轻轻地 好好地
Gently, gently. Nice. Nice.
现在放下铁棒
Now the iron.
还有枪
The gun.
放下 转过来
Down, down. Turn around.
看来我找到了些汽油 嗯？
Looks like I got myself some gasoline, eh?
嗯？V8的？
Eh? V8? Huh?
陷阱设好了 碰一下这些罐子就
Booby-trapped. Touch those tanks and:
陷阱 后退
Booby trap. Back up.
哦 你个狡猾的小子 你
Oh, you crafty little man, you.
反应很快 非常快
You're quick, very quick.
从没看过有人比蛇还快的 你是谁？
Never seen a man beat the snake before. Who are you?
生理反射作用 那是你拥有的
Reflexes. Yeah. That's what you've got.
我 我有头脑的
Me, I got brains.
嗨
Hey!
一个反应快的人…
A fella, a quick fella...
可能会藏武器在那下面 必须把他的头给顶着
...might have a weapon under there. I'd have to pin his head to the panel.
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey. Hey, hey...
别当我是傻子
Don't play me the fool.
汽油 燃料 汽油 有好几千加仑
Gas, fuel, gasoline! Thousands of gallons of it!
- 要多少有多少 - 在哪里？
- As much as you want! - Where? Where?
离这二十英里的地方 他们在挖油 炼油
Twenty miles from here. Pumping it, they are. Refining!
- 满满一油槽 - 胡扯
- A huge tanker full. - Crap.
不... 是真的 是真的
No. No, no, no, it's true! It's true.
不是自助式的 不 不 对我来说太难了
It's not self-service, no, no. It's too hard for me.
- 但像你这样聪明灵巧的人… - 在哪里？哪儿…？
- But a man of your ingenuity... - Where? Where? Where?
杀了我你就永远不知道了
Kill me and you'll never find out.
乖狗 乖狗
Good dog. Nice doggy, eh?
乖狗
Good doggy...
祝褔你 狗狗
Bless you, dog.
嗯… 在那儿
Well, there it is.
我在这里待了四天
Four days I was up here...
我和蛇儿们打麻将喝茶
...me and the snakes, playing mahjong, taking tea...
看着 想着…
...watching, thinking...
我要怎么进去弄到汽油？
...how was I gonna get in and get the gas?
日夜不停地抽取
Day and night it's pumping.
能烧的燃油
Fuel to burn.
他们什么都有 电力 灯 你想得到的都有
They've got the lot. Power, lights, you name it.
赌你的头他们会死守住
You can bet your life they mean to keep it.
里面有30个人
Thirty of them in there.
弓箭 火炮 枪
Arrows, flamethrowers, guns.
我觉得不适人类或爬虫居住
No place for man or reptile, I thought.
然后这个垃圾来了…
Then this trash arrived...
像飞峨扑火一样
...as moths to a flame.
一遍又一遍 攻击 攻击
Round and round, attack, attack...
像生气的蚂蚁 闻到汽油就发疯
...like angry ants, mad with the smell of gasoline.
他们贮油的地方… 在油槽
In the tanker, that's where they keep it.
上万加仑 要多少有多少
Thousands of gallons. As much as you want.
如果有人能进去 就是你了
If anyone's gonna get in there, it's gonna be you.
我呢 我得去喂蛇了
Me, I'm gonna feed the snakes.
我想一个人得信守诺言 我讲信用了 嗯？
A man lives by his word, I reckon, and I've kept mine, eh?
我们协定好了 我带你找到汽油 你让我走
Look, we had a deal. I show you the gas and you let me go, right?
- 原先的安排是我不杀你 - 我为你做了这些之后…
- The arrangement was I wouldn't kill you. - After all I've clone for you...
我觉得你很划算啊 不是吗？
I reckon you got a bargain, don't you?
攻击 害虫们 攻击
Attack, my vermin, attack!
(肉和青菜)
前进 给我抢燃料 为了荷蒙格斯的荣誉
Onward! Bring me the fuel. For the glory of Humungus.
为了伟大荷蒙格斯的荣誉
For the great glory of Humungus.
那混蛋向左边疯去了
Smegma crazies to the left!
大门… 变态的狂暴武士们到大门去
The gate! Gayboy berserkers to the gate!
我是你的老大
I am your Lord.
攻击
Attack!
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
不用了
Save it.
我是为了汽油来的
I'm just here for the gasoline.
是 是
Yeah. Yeah.
你高兴要多少都可以
As much as you like.
只要带我回去
Just take me back there.
拿起武器站出来吧
Show your weapons and come forward!
慢点
Steady now.
慢慢地
Take it real easy.
走到那里就够了
That's as far as you go.
转身
Turn around.
纳森 纳森 是纳森
Nathan! Nathan! It's Nathan!
快 拿担架
Hurry, get the stretcher!
丢下武器
Lose them.
开大门
Open the gate.
快拿担架来
Hurry up with that damned stretcher.
纳森
Nathan!
嘿 没事 就待在这儿
Hey, that's fine. It's fine. Just stay here.
看好他 看好他
Cover him. Cover him.
来 快 快
Come on, quick. Quick.
哦 太糟糕了
Oh, what a waste!
小心他的腿
Watch his leg.
看看你都干了什么
You and your handiwork!
他一点机会都没有了
He didn't stand a chance!
我警告过他 你们都听到了 我说“太疯狂了”
Oh, I warned him. You all heard me. "Madness," I said.
他说"我们可以带着我们的汽油逃"，我说"怎么逃?"
"We can escape, take our gas" he said. "How?" I said.
把那机器弄进去 查利 来帮我…
Get that machine inside. Charlie, help me...
德芮克
Derek?
拜托 把他放在桌上
Please, put him on the desk.
把机器拖进去
Get that machine inside.
关大门
Close the damned gate.
借过 借过…
Mind your backs, mind your backs. Corning through.
好 给他一些空间…
All right, give him room, give him room.
你是谁？
Who are you?
你怎么过来的？
How did you get through out there?
听着 我要答案 你在哪里找到他的？
Look, I want some answers. Where did you find him?
前面两三英里的地方 因为死了被留下的 我们有个协定
Two or three miles down the road, left for dead. We had a deal.
有另外三台车 有看到吗？
There were three other vehicles. Did you see them?
他们急急忙忙一直向西南开去
They're heading to the southwest in heaps of trouble.
他说如果我带他回来 你们会给我一些汽油
He said if I brought him back, you'd give me some gas.
- 现在没那么多闲功夫 - 车里有一个女的
- Now, there's not much time. - There was a woman in the car.
她死了
She's dead.
他们做了什么？
What did they do?
发生得很快 我只要我的汽油 想离开这里
It was quick. I just want my gas, I wanna get out of here.
他可能是他们之一 什么都别给
For all we know, he's one of them. Give him nothing.
她是对的 他是寄生虫
She's right, he's a parasite.
以人肉交易 魔鬼败类
Trading in human flesh. Mercenary trash.
- 我们有协定 - 什么意思？
- We had an arrangement. - What do you mean, an arrangement?
你去和他谈
You talk to this man.
不 试试什么 试点什么
No, no. Try something. Try something.
如果你有合约 是和他订的
If you had a contract, it was with him.
也和他一起死了
And it died With him.
- 把他赶走 - 走
- Get rid of him. - Move it.
左边
Left!
Left.
真是宝物一件 最后一个V8拦截者
Gotta hand it to you, treasure. The last of the V8 Interceptors.
历史的一部分
A piece of history.
把它炸掉真是一个耻辱
Would have been a shame to blow it up.
让他走
Let him go!
没事的 老兄
It's all right, mate.
关上大门 他们回来了
Here they come! Close the gates! They're coming back!
别开火 他没有恶意
Hold your fire! He comes in peace!
- 上帝 别开火 - 闭嘴
- For Christ's sake, hold your fire! - Shut up.
别开火
Hold your fire.
上帝 别开火
For Christ's sake, hold your fire.
来自荷蒙格斯的问候
Greetings from the Humungus!
荷蒙格斯大帝
The Lord Humungus!
荒地的战士
The Warrior of the Wasteland!
摇滚乐的阿亚图拉
The Ayatollah of Rock 'n' Roll-ah!
我非常失望
I am gravely disappointed.
你们再一次让我启动战事
Again you have made me unleash my dogs of war.
- 看看你们… - 救命
- Look at what remains... - Help!
- 勇猛的侦察兵都剩些什么 - 杀了他…
- ...of your gallant scouts. - Kill him now...
- 为什么？因为你们自私 - 一旦找到有机会
- Why? Because you're selfish. - ...while you've got the chance.
你们死藏着你们的汽油
You hoard your gasoline.
- 你们不讲道理 - 别听他讲
- You will not listen to reason. - Don't listen to him!
现在 我的囚犯说…
Now, my prisoners say...
你们计划把汽油移出荒地
...you plan to take your gasoline out of the wasteland.
今早你们派他们出去找车子
You sent them out this morning to find a vehicle.
找一台够大的车来拖那个肥油库
A rig big enough to haul that fat tank of gas.
多么卑鄙的计划
What a puny plan.
你们看看四周
Look around you.
这里是死亡谷
This is the Valley of Death.
看
See!
什么也逃不出去 荷蒙格斯统的治荒地
Nothing can escape! The Humungus rules the wasteland!
什么都不要给他们 炸掉它 什么都不要给…
Give them nothing. Blow it up. Give them...
荷蒙格斯没那么好惹
Humungus will not be defied.
魏兹 魏兹
Wez. Wez.
- 听好了 - 哈
- Listen to me! - Aah!
我来 我来
I got it. I got it.
很好
Good one.
安静 安静 别再玩了
Quiet. Quiet. No more games.
别再玩了
No more games!
我们是有目的而来的
We are here for a purpose.
我们有个提案
We've come with an offer.
不 不必再谈
No. No more talk.
我们进去 我们杀
We go in. We kill.
我们杀了他们
We'll kill them!
我们杀他们 杀了他们
We'll kill them! Kill them. Kill them!
你看见他了吗？
Do you see him?
杀…
Kill! Kill!
不要动 我的战狗
Be still, my dog of war.
我了解你的痛苦
I understand your pain.
我们都失去过心爱的人 但我们照我的方法做
We all lost someone we love. But we do it my way.
输家才会等待
Losers. Losers wait.
我们照我的方法做
We do it my way.
恐惧是我们的同盟 汽油会是我们的
Their fear is our ally. The gasoline will be ours.
然后你可以复仇
Then you shall have your revenge.
带走他
Take him away.
已经有太多的暴力 太多痛苦
There has been too much violence, too much pain.
这儿一切都有罪
None here are without sin.
但我有一个真诚的和解方案
But I have an honorable compromise.
离开这儿
Just walk away.
把泵…
Give me the pump...
原油…
...the oil...
汽油…
...the gasoline...
和整个营区都给我 我就饶了你们的命
...and the whole compound, and I'll spare your lives.
离开这儿 我会让你们安全的通过荒地
Just walk away. I will give you safe passage in the wasteland.
只要离开 恐惧就能结束
Just walk away and there will be an end to the horror.
我等你们的回答
I await your answer.
你们有一整天来决定
You have one full day to decide.
我们绝不离开
We'll never walk away!
绝不
Never!
你听到他说的话了 听来很合理
You heard what he said. It sounds reasonable.
我们不必死
We don't have to die.
只要离开这儿
All we have to do is walk away.
不 我们苦心经营这么久
No. We've worked too hard.
很简单 我们只要用燃料
It's simple. All we do is change the fuel...
和这个废车场来换我们的命
...and this junkyard for our lives.
他们欲擒故纵 想把我们像杀猪般宰了
Look, if we walk out there, they'll slaughter us.
他们会放开我们 然后向杀猪一般地砍了我们
They'll set us loose and then cut us down like pigs.
别听他们的话
Don't listen to them.
好 好 就这样
All right. All right. This is it.
我会和这个荷蒙格斯谈谈
I'll talk to this Humungus.
他是个明事理的人…
He's a reasonable man...
愿意接受谈判
...open to negotiation.
他答应给我们一条生路 他承诺了
He promised us safe passage. He gave his word.
让我们假设他守信…
And let us suppose he keeps it...
我们可以保住性命离开这里 然后呢？
...and we walk away from here with our lives. What then?
但记住
But remember.
记住一件事 比一槽油更重要的事
Remember one thing. That is more than just a tanker of gas.
那就是我们能在 机器害虫之外生存
That is our lifeline to a place beyond that vermin on machines.
那是离这儿两千英里以外
That's 2000 miles from here!
你想我们要怎么到达那儿？用拖的吗？
How do you expect us to get it there? Drag it?
如果必须如此 是的 总有办法的
If we have to, yes. There's always a way.
但第一步是
But the first step...
保护好燃料
...defend the fuel.
空话
Words.
都是空话
Just words!
你会为了白日梦死的
You'd die for a pipe dream!
错了 我们为了信仰而战 我要留下
Wrong. We fight for a belief. I stay.
我希望能成功 帕帕盖洛
I wish it could have worked, Pappagallo.
你不能要我们和那些人对抗
You can't expect to compete with that.
我们一天比一天弱 他们一天比一天强 结束了
Every day we get weaker while they get stronger. It's finished.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
两天前 我看到一台能拖动那只油槽的车
Two days ago I saw a vehicle that'd haul that tanker.
你们想离开这里…
You wanna get out of here...
和我谈
...you talk to me.
好 这是我的提议
Okay, so that's my offer.
我负责一台够大能拖动油槽的车…
I deliver a rig big enough to haul that tanker...
你们把我的车还我 以及我能带得动的汽油
...you give me back my vehicle and as much juice as I can carry.
我们今早失去了8个人
We lost eight good people this morning.
他在想什么？
What's he got in mind?
我需要5加仑柴油
Now, to do the job I need five gallons of diesel...
和一些高能量的汽油来办这件事
...and some high-octane gasoline.
当作是预付款吧
Think of it as a down payment.
这会是最后一次看到他
And that's the last we'll ever see of him.
他会回来拿他的车
He has to come back for his wheels.
我们能损失什么？
What have we got to lose?
说定了
You've got yourself a deal.
我的车和我能载得动的油
My vehicle and all the juice I can carry.
来 狗狗
Come on, dog.
嘘…
Shh!
你知道我最怀念什么吗？干净的女人
You know what I miss most of all? Clean women.
指甲油 香水…
Nail polish, perfume...
脚踏车坐垫的味道 鸡尾酒…
...the smell of bicycle seats, cocktails...
- 闭嘴 - 甜点
- Shut up. - Desserts.
内衣 记得内衣吗？
Lingerie. Remember lingerie?
我就知道 我知道会有用的
I knew it. I knew it'd work.
真要命 这些蛇 天生的杀手
Lethal. Lethal, these snakes. Born killers.
坐下
Down!
是我的蛇 我训练出来的 让我吃掉它
It's my snake. I trained it. I'm gonna eat it.
去找你自己的 放手
So find your own. Get out of it.
我有煮蛇的食谱 很美味的
I've got a recipe for snake. Delicious.
爬虫炖肉丁 走开
Fricassee of reptile. Get out.
比你的狗食好 不
Better than your dog food. No!
纯蛋白质 矿物质 维他命
Pure protein, minerals, vitamins.
人一定要照顾自己
A man's gotta look after himself.
健康的心灵 健康的身体 狗儿
Healthy mind, healthy body, dog.
你吃什么就成为什么 走开
Hey! You are what you eat, I reckon. Get away!
你们两个该照照镜子
You two ought to take a look in the mirror some time.
没品味 没水准
No style, no taste.
空的
Empty...
搞了半天
All this time.
不诚实 下流
That's dishonest. Low.
看看你那台车
Let's have a look at this machine of yours.
我怎么知道那是不是坏的？
How do I know that one's not a dud?
- 来看看 - 没事 没事
- Find out. - Cool. Cool, cool.
你必须了解基本的空气动力学 像这个
Now, you've gotta understand the basics of aerodynamics in a thing like this.
闭嘴…
Shut up. Shut up.
嘿 嘿 嘿…
Hey! Hey, hey, hey.
那我呢？你不会把我留下来吧
What about me, eh? You're not gonna leave me here, are you?
你爱干嘛干嘛
Do what you want.
我们是伙伴
We're partners.
你和我 我们是伙伴
You and me, we're partners.
伙伴
Partners!
走 走
Go. Go.
- 呜 - 哈
- Whoo! - Aah!
我的狗儿 跑 大门
My dogs, run. The gate.
大门 大门 打开大门
The gate. The gate. The gate.
你 你能跑 但你躲不掉的
You. You can run, but you can't hide.
做的好
You did a great job.
我的好伙伴
That's my man.
别过份了
Don't go overboard now.
不 不要碰 拜托 这东西很宝贝的
No, don't touch, please. It's a precision instrument.
别碰
Don't touch.
哈 哈 哈
Ah, ah, ah.
不要碰
Don't touch.
走开
Shoo, shoo. Go.
去 去
Shoo! Shoo!
走开
Go.
告诉我 你这台机器…
Tell me, son, this machine of yours...
可以载两个人吧？
...it can take two, can it?
可能吧
Possibly.
你还好吗？
All right?
我没事 把大家组织起来 我们今晚走
I'm okay. Just get them organized, we're moving out tonight.
好 大家听着 我们今晚出发
Okay, listen, everyone. We're going out tonight.
你们都知道该做什么 照计划进行
You all know what to do, just get on with it.
提波 德芮克 帕帕盖洛受伤了
Timbo, Derek, Pappagallo's been hurt.
车子怎么样？
How's the rig?
车子 车子怎么样？
The rig. How is she?
盖子裂了
A cracked timing case cover.
坏了齿轮上的两个齿子
It's broken some teeth off the timing gears.
盖子有裂痕
It's got a cracked timing case cover.
齿轮掉了两个齿
It's broken a couple of teeth off the timing gears.
- 冷却器核心受损 - 冷却器核心受损
- The radiator's damaged at the core. - The radiator's damaged at the core.
- 水箱裂了 - 水箱出现一条断裂缝
- A cracked water pump. - It's got a cracked water pump.
- 还有裂开的注油器线 - 还有裂开的注油器线
- And a fractured injector line. - And it's got a fractured injector line.
好吧 这些意味着什么？
Well, what does all that mean?
哦 好吧 这些意味着什么？
Yeah, okay, but what does that mean?
- 意味着什么？ - 24小时
- What does that mean? - Twenty-four hours.
24小时
Twenty-four hours.
他们有12小时
They've got 12.
- 你们只有12小时 - 好
- You've got 12. - Okay.
好
0Kay.
把他搬下来 快 来
Let's get him down. Quick, come on.
我原先错看你了…
Listen, I was wrong about you...
对不起
...and I'm sorry.
没关系 他没事
All right, he's all right.
很久没看到有人那样开车了
It's been a long time since I've seen driving like that, man.
我觉得你很好
You're okay by me, son.
有你开那台车 我们赢定了 有你一起不错
With you driving that rig, we got it licked! Nice to have you aboard, son.
我存了很久 请你收下
I've been saving those. I want you to have them.
谢谢你 不客气
Thank you, and welcome.
很高兴和你们做生意 但我要离开了
It's been a pleasure doing business with you, but I'm leaving.
我要走了 谢谢
I'm leaving. Thanks.
我的天 看
Oh, my God, look!
在山上
Up on the hill!
那些混蛋要吊死他们
They're stringing them up, the bastards!
看
Look!
你们违抗了我
You have defied me.
你们会看到 荷蒙格斯大帝的复仇
You will know the vengeance of Lord Humungus.
我答应你们…
I promise you...
没有人…
...nobody...
没有人能活着离开这里
...nobody gets out of here alive.
谁来帮忙我弄这些滚筒 该死的 来啊
Who's supposed to be helping out with the drums? Come on!
嘿 别忘了 在我们离开之前一点也不要浪费
Hey, don't forget, don't waste a bit before we leave.
快 抓住那些猪
Just wanna catch the pigs.
快来弄滚筒 来
Come on with the drums, come on!
有人在那儿帮忙吗？
Is anybody helping over there?
嘿 快来
Hey, come on!
怎么了？来啊
What's wrong? Come on.
这样溜开好像不太对
It just seems really wrong, sneaking away like this.
什么？
What?
可是你说你想来的 甜心
But you said you wanted to come, sweetheart.
我知道我这么说过
I know I did, but...
看 你被吓到了 来 那里将会是安全的
Look, you're scared. Now, come on, it'll be much safer up there.
- 我们在等什么？- 不要
- What are we waiting for, eh? - No, don't.
这是我的家
This is my family.
我不要离开这些人
I'm not gonna leave these people.
我要留下来
I'm staying.
对不起
I'm sorry.
拜托 把它们放到一起
Come on, keep it together.
我告诉你了 他要走了 我怎么说来着？
I told you, he's leaving. What did I tell you?
看 他要离开了
Look, he's leaving.
我必须长话短说 我要你开油槽车
Look, I don't have time for long speeches. I want you to drive the tanker.
抱歉
Sorry.
我们有约定 我做到了我的部分
We had a contract. I kept my part of the bargain.
我们可以订新合约
We'll make a new contract.
我需要的都在这儿
I've got all I need here.
你没有未来 我可以提供你一个未来 重建我们的生活
You don't have a future. I could offer you that. Rebuild our lives.
麦克斯
Max...
买一张二千英里的票
...buy a ticket for 2000 miles.
孩子 你一定要来 我们要去这儿 乐园
You have to come, sonny. This is where we're going. Paradise.
离这儿二千英里
Two thousand miles from here.
清新的水 阳光满天
Fresh water, plenty of sunshine.
除了养儿育女没事可做
Nothing to do but breed.
不 谢了
No, thanks.
你是怎么回事？你在找什么？
What is it with you, huh? What are you looking for?
麦克斯 每个人都在寻觅
Come on, Max, everyone's looking for something.
你在外面很高兴？
You happy out there, are you?
流浪？日复一日地过着？
Eh? Wandering? One day blurring into another?
麦克斯 你是腐食动物 就像蛆
You're a scavenger, Max. You're a maggot.
你知道吗？
Do you know that?
你靠旧世界的死尸过活
You're living off the corpse of the old world.
告诉我你的故事 说吧 告诉我你的故事
Tell me your story. Come on, tell me your story.
什么让你无动于衷的？
What burned you out?
杀了太多人？
Kill one man too many?
看到太多人死？死了亲人？
See too many people die? Lose some family?
原来如此 你失去了亲人 这让你很特别？
Oh, so that's it. You lost some family. That make you something special, does it?
听我说
Listen to me.
你以为你是唯一受苦的吗？
Do you think you're the only one that's suffered?
我们在这儿都经历过这些 但我们并不放弃
We've all been through it in here. But we haven't given up.
我们还是有尊严的人
We're still human beings with dignity.
但你 你离开这里就是个垃圾
But you, you're out there with the garbage.
你什么也不是
You're nothing.
出去 孩子
Get out, kid.
去 出去
Come on, get out of here.
去 出去 赶快走开 出去
Go on, get out. Scat. Get out.
你让他走
You're letting him go?
至少留住他的车
Well, let's keep his vehicle, at least.
他完成了他的约定 他是一个值得尊敬的的人
He fulfilled his contract. He's an honorable man.
好 那谁来开油槽车
Okay, so who's gonna drive the tanker?
我
I am.
你们看错你了 你不是懦夫
They've got you wrong, you're not a coward.
也许笨 但不是懦夫
Stupid maybe, but not a coward.
你正犯一个严重的错误
You're making a serious mistake...
破坏我们的团队
...splitting a great team.
你和我一起 想想所有的可能
You and me together, think of the possibilities.
或许会再见面 再见 祝你好运
See you around, maybe. Goodbye, good luck.
我们走
We go!
你这只小狗 你违背了我
You disobey me. You puppy.
(二氧化氮)
陶蒂 汽油 快点
Toadie, the gas. Hurry up.
别杀他 如果他还活着…
Don't waste him. If he's alive...
我要他
...I want him.
油箱是满的 伟大的魏兹 都是你的
The tanks are full, O mighty Wez, and it's all yours!
结束了
It's all over.
我们走
Let's go.
看 那儿 西北
Look, out there. Northwest.
老天
Oh, hell.
你搞砸了 你个笨蛋
You blew it, you fool.
放轻松 伙伴
Relax, partner.
我来开油槽车
I'll be driving the tanker.
我们会撞毁 或是撞过去
We're gonna crash or crash through.
现在 此时 他们只想要油槽
Now, at this point, that's all they want. The tanker.
所以他们会直接追过来
So they'll come straight after us.
我们用那个来突围…
So we'll use that to punch our way out...
那将给你们一个很好的机会
...which will give all of you a very, very good chance.
不要犹豫
Now, don't hesitate.
一旦你出去了 尽自己努力离开
Once you're outside there, split up and go as hard as you can.
向北200英里…
Now, 200 miles to the north...
有一个叫大力河的地方有座桥
...there's a place with a bridge called Powder River.
那是我们的集合点
That's our rendezvous.
等到日落时
Give us till sunset.
如果到时我们还没到… 就继续走
If we haven't made it by then, keep going.
我够资格修理 没资格坐？
Good enough for me to build, but not to ride on?
- 你不准上油槽车 - 我流血流汗
- You are not coming on this tanker! - I sweated blood on this...
却没人叫我去坐校车
...and no bastard's gonna tell me to ride in no school bus!
好 别吵了
Okay, settle down!
如果对你没差别…
If it's all the same to you...
我来开油槽车
...I'll drive that tanker.
那个提议 已经没了 想订约太晚了
The offer is closed. Too late for deals.
不必订约 我想开那台车
No deals. I wanna drive that truck.
为什么突然改变心意？
Why? Why the big change of heart?
相信我 我没有选择
Believe me, I haven't got a choice.
你想你要怎么办到？
And how do you think you'll do it?
我是说 看看你 连轮椅都开不了
I mean, look at you. You couldn't even drive a wheelchair.
麦克斯 你应该看看你自己 一团糟
You should look at yourself, Max. You're a mess.
好了 别再多说
Come on, cut the crap.
我是你最好的机会
I'm the best chance you've got.
好 走吧
Right, let's get moving.
移开那孩子 弄走他
Move that kid! Get rid of him!
可恶
Oh, shit!
走 走 走…
Go! Go, go, go, go!
我没事 我没事
I'm all right, I'm all right.
快开 快开
Move it. Move it.
快 快 快
Come on, come on, come on!
哇…
Whoa!
轮胎 射轮胎
The tire! Shoot the tire!
孩子 快 跳
Boy! Come on, jump!
快 跳
Come on, jump!
我说
I say.
我们赢了
We've won.
结束了 孩子
It's over, boy.
嘿 孩子
Hey, kid.
去拿子弹 子弹
Get the bullet. The bullet.
起来 加油
Get up. Go on.
拿弹壳
Get the shell.
弹壳
快 快 去
Come on. Come on, go!
于是开始朝北奔向安全的旅程…
And so began the journey north to safety...
到我们在阳光下的土地
...to our place in the sun.
我们之中 找到了新领导人 从天而降的…
Among us we found a new leader, the man who came from the sky...
那位摘罗机长
...the Gyro Captain.
正如帕帕盖洛计划的…
And just as Pappagallo had planned...
我们远远离开了 机器害虫的地盘
...we traveled far beyond the reach of men on machines.
油 宝贵的油 藏在车子里
The juice, the precious juice, was hidden in the vehicles.
我呢 长大成人
As for me, I grew to manhood...
过了许多时间 我成了…
...in the fullness of time, I became the leader...
大北部落的领导人
...the chief of the Great Northern Tribe.
而公路战士
And the Road Warrior?
那是我们最后一次见到他
That was the last we ever saw of him.
他现在活在… 我的记忆里
He lives now only in my memories.